#### Evan Madden

(856) 571 - 4345 | <a href="mailto:evan.madden@gmail.com">evan.madden@gmail.com</a> | Philadelphia, PA 19148 GitHub: /EvMad | Portfolio: <a href="https://evmad.github.io/portfolio-one/">https://evmad.github.io/portfolio-one/</a> LinkedIn Profile: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/evan-madden-923474211/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/evan-madden-923474211/</a>

#### **Summary:**

Full Stack Web developer with an event production background, a Full Stack (MERN) Web Development Certificate from the University of Pennsylvania, a BA in Music Technology, and a UX Design Certificate. Soft skills developed over a decade of managing client experience and event production.

#### **Technical Skills, Languages, and Frameworks:**

HTML, HTML5, XML, XHTML, Markup, PHP, Regex, htaccess, CSS, SCSS, Sass, CSS frameworks, Bulma, Bootstrap, JavaScript, ECMAScript, JSX, vanilla JavaScript, TypeScript, jQuery, Jest, OOP, Git, Git Bash, version control, CLI, Github, Heroku, deployment, FTP, MERN, React, React Router, Redux, React Hooks, DOM, Virtual DOM, Node.js, Node, NPM, Inquirer.js, Moment.js, Webpack, PWA, Progressive Web App, ServiceWorker.js, Manifest, Responsive Web Design, Express, Express.js, API, APIs, RESTful, REST, Ajax, Insomnia Core, Handlebars.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, GraphQL, Apollo, Apollo Server, Atlas, MongoDB Atlas, non-relational database, SQL, MySQL, Workbench, Sequelize, Sequelize.js, relational database, SOQL, Salesforce, Apex, Visualforce, AutoRabit, CRM, Kanban, Trello, Jira, SharePoint, Azure, Azure DevOps, DevOps, AWS, Scrum, Agile, UI Design, WCAG, Accessibility, User Centered Design, Adobe XD, Figma, UX, UI, UX/UI, UI/UX, UX Research, UX Design, User Stories, Personas, DCM, Cloudinary, Digital Content Management, Debugging

### **Relevant Employment:**

Web Specialist : ECFMG Philadelphia, PA July 2022 - Present https://www.ecfmg.org/ | https://www.faimer.org/

Responsible for building new components, maintaining existing applications, improving accessibility, developing remotely within a team using Git version control, completing work packets through Trello, and completing sprints through Azure DevOps.

- Attends daily huddles with the editorial staff and standups with the front-end team, as well as planning meetings to coordinate with the larger communications department.
  - Participates in standups for Azure DevOps sprints.
- Works on a team of four developers. Interfaces with a second team of six developers.
  - Builds new components using JavaScript and XML
    - Debugs existing components
  - Refactored and migrated legacy sites using modern frameworks.

- See EPIC project: <a href="https://www.ecfmg.org/psv/">https://www.ecfmg.org/psv/</a> for full refactor of an old site. Completed four days ahead of schedule.
  - Uses CSS and Bulma to integrate multimedia, as well as create new buttons and other components.
    - Follows branding and style guidelines for all work packets.
    - Formats content for HTML emails, and integrates WordPress into larger PHP sites.
    - Completed Salesforce Developer training modules up to "Trailhead Ranger" level.
- Tools: Trello, Azure DevOps, Microsoft Teams, HTML, JavaScript, XML, CSS, SCSS, Sass, Bulma, PHP, WordPress, XHTML, htaccess, Regex, Git Bash, AutoRabit, Salesforce, Markup, Microsoft Word, Adobe, Photoshop, User Stories, UX

## Venue Manager : Kung Fu Necktie Philadelphia, PA March 2015 - July 2022

Promoted from bartender to keyholder to manager for a live music venue. Coordinated event staff (booking, security, sound, and bar.) Engaged and retained new clients. Curated artist and guest experiences. Assisted with construction and renovation projects.

• Tools: Google Calendar, Google Sheets, PrismFM, Social Media, Ticket Fly, Eventbrite

#### **Education:**

**University of Pennsylvania** - Full Stack Web Development Certificate May 2021 - August 2021

- Completed over 20 applications.
- Contributed to three group projects.
- Graduated from the full-time program with a 3.4 GPA
- Built several full-stack applications.
- Built middleware, API's, and server-side applications.

### Google UX Design by Google on Coursera

Certificate earned January 25, 2023

- Created paper wireframes and prototypes
- Created User Stories, Problem Statements and Personas
- Created digital wireframes and prototypes using Figma and Adobe XD
- Created high-fidelity mockups and prototypes using Figma and Adobe XD
- Presented work as case studies and deployed through Github

**University of Maryland Baltimore County -** BA in Music, Recording Emphasis Linehan Artist Scholar Program

# **Projects:**

# **React Blog**

Deployed: <a href="https://bit.ly/3LxrBoA">https://bit.ly/3dvfEmL</a> Repo: <a href="https://bit.ly/3dvfEmL">https://bit.ly/3dvfEmL</a> React and Node front-end blog mockup, deployed via Heroku.

# Note-taker

Deployed: <a href="https://bit.ly/3NeDWyJ">https://bit.ly/3zk6Fwk</a>

Note taking app created with Node, Express, and FS, deployed with Heroku.

# **Community Canvas**

Deployed: <a href="https://bit.ly/3CthrQx">https://bit.ly/3k2TZCE</a>

Community Canvas is a full stack application developed for users to upload and view photos of street art, created with JavaScript, Sequelize, and MySQL. This role focused on learning to use Cloudinary as a digital assets management platform, as well as creating a mobile-first design.